ROLL-CHAN WORLD
Hacked by Zynk Oxhyde
2017

--------------
Date Released:
--------------
v1.0 March 26, 2017; In commemoration of Rockman/Mega Man 29th Anniversary and beyond! Yay! XD
v2.0 June 9, 2024; In commemoration of Rockman/Mega Man 36th Anniversary AND Roll-chan 10th Anniversary and beyond! Yay! XD

------------
Description:
------------
This is a player sprite hack of "Mega Man: Dr. Wily's Revenge" for the Gameboy!
This hack changes Mega Man's player sprites and other illustrations of him into his sister Roll! 

There are three (3) Roll-chan skins to choose from:
* Megaman 1 (Classic) Roll-chan
* Megaman 8 Roll-chan
* Megaman 11 Roll-chan

------
Story:
------
After Dr. Wily's defeat against the Super Fighting Robot Girl, Roll-chan, he already has
set his scheme for his revenge. Dr. Wily was able to reconstruct the Robot Masters that he
stole from Dr. Light's laboratory and the robots that he originally made! Other than that, 
Dr. Wily created a new "Roll Killer" named Enker, specifically made to eliminate Roll.

Roll is sent into battle once again and go after Dr. Wily, who has acquired a new castle and
his very own space station!

FIGHT, ROLL-CHAN! FOR EVERLASTING PEACE ONCE MORE!!

--------
Changes:
--------
(v2.0 - 06/09/2024)
*Every Roll-chan sprites updated
*Newer Get Weapon Roll sprite art
*Added Megaman 11 Roll-chan skin

(v1.0 - 03/26/2017)
*New Roll-chan player sprites
*New Get Weapon Roll sprite art
*Titlescreen modified
*New fonts
*Some enemies' colors fixed, e.g. Changkeys, Schworms
*Fixed Dr. Wily's palettes
*Ending sprites

---------
Controls:
---------
A - Jump
B - Shoot
Left/Right - Run
Up/Down - Climb ladders
Start - Weapons Menu

------
Items:
------
Small life energy
Large life energy
Small weapon energy
Large weapon energy
1UP

--------
Weapons:
--------
RO - Roll Buster 	- Default weapon.
IC - Ice Slasher 	- Weapon got from Ice Man. Freezes foes on spot. Very useful against enemies throughout the game.
CU - Rolling Cutter 	- Weapon got from Cut Man. Acts like a boomerang. Does multiple hits to an enemy.
EL - Thunder Beam	- Weapon got from Elec Man. Three beams of electricity shot simultaneously in 3 directions.
FI - Fire Storm 	- Weapon got from Fire Man. Firing a shot activates a temporary fireball barrier.
FL - Time Stopper 	- Weapon got from Flash Man. Stops everything from moving until weapon energy is depleted. Useless against most bosses.
QU - Quick Boomerang 	- Weapon got from Quick Man. A volley of boomerangs shot midrange. Hold B for continuous shooting.
BU - Bubble Lead 	- Weapon got from Bubble Man. A bubble acts like a bowling ball. Strong against large enemies.
HE - Atomic Fire 	- Weapon got from Heat Man. Holding B charges it making a large fireball. Can destroy destructible walls.
EN - Mirror Buster 	- Weapon got from Enker. A barrier in front of the player that reflects projectiles. 
CA - Carry 		- A support unit. A platform deployed in front of the player when grounded, or beneath the player in mid air. Available after defeating the first 4 Robot Masters.

---------
ZIP file:
---------
ROLL-CHAN WORLD_GB folder
1. This readme
2. RCW1-GB-MM1_v2.ips
3. RCW1-GB-MM8_v2.ips
4. RCW1-GB-MM11_v2.ips

-----------------
How to use patch:
-----------------
Use Lunar IPS to apply patches. Do not apply one patch over the other. Refer to the ROM Information on which ROM the patch is to be applied over.

----------------
ROM Information:
----------------
File Name:	Megaman - Dr. Wily's Revenge (U) [!].gb	
File Size:	262,144	
CRC32:		47E70E08	
MD5:		4BA4398181D98958FA7434BA7716F11A	
SHA1:		277EDB3C844E812BA4B3EB9A96C9C30414541858

--------
Credits:
--------
Zynk Oxhyde - Hacking and Sprites and illustrations

----------
Utilities:
----------
YY-CHR by YY
WindHex hex editor by Bongo`
bgb emulator - http://bgb.bircd.org/
Mesen emulator - https://www.mesen.ca/

---------------
Special Thanks:
---------------
Romhacking.net 	- for hosting the patch
Sprite's Inc. 	- for the ripped sprites of Roll from various Rockman/Mega Man games (http://www.sprites-inc.co.uk/)

--------
Contact:
--------
Email: zynkoxhyde@yahoo.com

----------------------------
Disclaimer and Terms of Use:
----------------------------
*Zynk Oxhyde is not related or affiliated with Nintendo and the publisher of the original game.
*Do not sell this patch and the contents with it.
*Do not sell the pre-patched ROM into reproduction cartridges.
*You may distribute or host this patch provided that all files that come with it are intact.