ROLL-CHAN WORLD 4
Hacked by Zynk Oxhyde
2017

--------------
Date Released:
--------------
v1.0 March 26, 2017; In commemoration of Rockman/Mega Man 29th Anniversary and beyond! Yay! XD

------------
Description:
------------
This is a player sprite hack of "Mega Man IV" for the Gameboy!
This hack changes Mega Man's player sprites and other illustrations of him into his sister Roll! 

------
Story:
------
The world is at peace after Dr. Wily's defeat thanks to Roll. During that time, a World Robot Expo
was held and scientists all over the globe gathered to show their creations. Nevertheless, Dr. Wily,
who went missing in action, suddenly arrived in the event with his Robot Masters wreaking havoc.
He managed to capture 4 key areas and reprogrammed the robots around the world to help him on his
machinations yet again.

Roll managed to evade Dr. Wily reprogramming thanks to Dr. Light. With the world in chaos, she is the
only one with the power to stop Dr. Wily's Robot Masters. She needs to recapture the 4 key areas and 
defeat Dr. Wily, who currently commandeered a huge tank base and a battleship in space! It also houses
Dr. Wily's newest creations: "Roll Killer" Ballade and a colossal robot.

Joining her adventure is Tango the robot cat, Eddie the robot can, and Beat the robot attack bird!

FIGHT, ROLL-CHAN! FOR EVERLASTING PEACE ONCE MORE!!

--------
Changes:
--------
(v1.0 - 03/26/2017)
*New Roll-chan player sprites
*New Get Weapon Roll sprite art
*Titlescreen modified
*New fonts
*The Intro and other scenes replaces Mega Man with Roll
*Rush Coil to Tango Coil
*Rush Jet to Tango Jet
*Some text revisions
*Ending sprites

---------
Controls:
---------
A - Jump
B - Shoot; Hold it down for a Charged Shot
Left/Right - Run
Up/Down - Climb ladders
A+Down - Slide
Start - Weapons Menu
Select - Press on the Stage Select screen to enter Dr. Light's Lab.

------
Items:
------
Small life energy
Large life energy
Small weapon energy
Large weapon energy
1UP
Small E-can - collect 4 of these to get 1 E-can.
E-can - fully replenishes life energy. Player can only hold 4 cans.
Small P-chips - collect these to trade for items and powerups in Dr. Light's Lab. Each is worth 2 points.
Large P-chips - collect these to trade for items and powerups in Dr. Light's Lab. Each is worth 8 points.
Eddie - a walking can robot that can be found in some stages. He gives away a random item.
BEAT plates - collect all B, E, A, and T plates to get Beat.
WILY plates - collect all W, I, L, and Y plates to open the shutters Wily's Tank.

----------------------
Dr. Light's Lab items:
----------------------
Energy Balancer - restores weapon with the least energy when picking up weapon energy.
W-can - fully restores weapon energy of one weapon.
S-can - fully restores all life and weapons energy.
Weapon Charger - fully restores all your weapons energy. Can be done in the Lab.

--------
Weapons:
--------
RO - Roll Buster 	- Default weapon. Hold down the B-button for a Charged Shot.
TC - Tango Coil		- A spring adaptor for Tango. Used for jumping on high platforms. Obtained after defeating Toad Man.
TJ - Tango Jet		- A jet board adaptor for Tango. Flies in a straight line. Obtained after defeating Charge Man.
TO - Rain Flush		- Weapon got from Toad Man. Summon rain that damages all enemies on the screen. Can put out fires.
BR - Flash Stopper	- Weapon got from Bright Man. Freezes enemy activity for a short time. The player can shoot buster shots in that duration.
PH - Pharaoh Shot	- Weapon got from Pharaoh Man. A shot that can be thrown diagonally in any direction. Hold down the B-button to charge a large energy ball.
RI - Ring Boomerang	- Weapon got from Ring Man. A ring that can collect an item when thrown.
CR - Crystal Eye	- Weapon got from Crystal Man. A large crystal ball that scatters into 3 small orbs that bounce on walls.
NA - Napalm Bomb	- Weapon got from Napalm Man. A bomb capsule that bounces on floors until it explodes.
ST - Power Stone	- Weapon got from Stone Man. Summon 3 rocks orbiting around the player.
CH - Charge Kick	- Weapon got from Charge Man. Attack enemies by sliding.
BA - Ballade Cracker	- Weapon got from Ballade. A bomb that can be thrown in any direction.
BE - Beat		- Summon Beat the robot bird to attack nearby enemies.

----
Tip:
----
Get over 4 Game Overs in one stage and you will start in Dr. Light's Lab. The good doctor will enhance your Charged Shot making it wider.

---------
ZIP file:
---------
ROLL-CHAN WORLD 4_GB folder
1. This readme
2. RW4-GB-CLASSIC.ips
3. RW4-GB-MM8.ips

-----------------
How to use patch:
-----------------
Use Lunar IPS to apply patches. Do not apply one patch over the other. Refer to the ROM Information on which ROM the patch is to be applied over.

----------------
ROM Information:
----------------
File Name:	Megaman IV (U) [!].gb
File Size:	524,288	
CRC32:		ABCEA00D
MD5:		8A00F627B8902C92327435901C249E19
SHA1:		6F0901DB2B5DCAACE0215C0ABDC21A914FA21B65

--------
Credits:
--------
Zynk Oxhyde - Hacking and Sprites and illustrations

----------
Utilities:
----------
YY-CHR by YY
WindHex hex editor by Bongo`
bgb emulator - http://bgb.bircd.org/

---------------
Special Thanks:
---------------
Romhacking.net 	- for hosting the patch
Sprite's Inc. 	- for the ripped sprites of Roll from various Rockman/Mega Man games (http://www.sprites-inc.co.uk/)

--------
Contact:
--------
Email: zynkoxhyde@yahoo.com

----------------------------
Disclaimer and Terms of Use:
----------------------------
*Zynk Oxhyde is not related or affiliated with Nintendo and the publisher of the original game.
*Do not sell this patch and the contents with it.
*Do not sell the pre-patched ROM into reproduction cartridges.
*You may distribute or host this patch provided that all files that come with it are intact.