ROLL-CHAN WORLD 5
Hacked by Zynk Oxhyde
2017

--------------
Date Released:
--------------
v1.0 March 26, 2017; In commemoration of Rockman/Mega Man 29th Anniversary and beyond! Yay! XD

------------
Description:
------------
This is a player sprite hack of "Mega Man V" for the Gameboy!
This hack changes Mega Man's player sprites and other illustrations of him into his sister Roll! 

------
Story:
------
With Dr. Wily disappearence, Roll and the world enjoyed peace. A few months later, a new threat has 
arrived on Earth, the Stardroids - alien robots from space. The Stardroids is lead by a robot named 
Terra. One day, he challenged Roll, who was taking a vacation in Russia with Kalinka. Roll lost because
her weapons are not effective against Terra. While she was out, the Stardroids commenced their attack
on Earth. However, Dr. Light managed to restore Roll and outfitted her with a new weapon, the "Roll Arm",
replaces the Roll Buster charged shot. She also has Tango, her robot cat, who can now support her in battle
with his rolling attack and his ususal support transformations. The Stardroids are on the loose not only on
Earth but in other planets as well, and only the Super Robot Girl Roll-chan can stop them!

FIGHT, ROLL-CHAN! DEAFEAT THE STARDROIDS! FOR EVERLASTING PEACE ONCE MORE!!

--------
Changes:
--------
(v1.1 - 04/01/2017)
*Fixed air bubble sprite
*Fixed texts errors

(v1.0 - 03/26/2017) - initial release
*New Roll-chan player sprites
*New Get Weapon Roll sprite art
*Titlescreen modified
*New fonts
*The Intro and other scenes replaces Mega Man with Roll
*Rush Coil to Tango Coil
*Rush Jet to Tango Jet
*Rush Space to Tango Space
*New icons for Magic Hand (MH) and Roll Claw (CL)
*Quint to Quart (Note: Her name is from "Quartet" as Quint from "Quintet", a musical term)
*Some text revisions
*Some stage palettes changed
*Added Kalinka in the prolog

---------
Controls:
---------
A - Jump
B - Shoot; Hold it down to shoot the Roll Arm
Left/Right - Run
Up/Down - Climb ladders
A+Down - Slide
Start - Weapons Menu
Select - Press on the Stage Select screen to enter Dr. Light's Lab.

------
Items:
------
Small life energy
Large life energy
Small weapon energy
Large weapon energy
1UP
Small E-can - collect 4 of these to get 1 E-can.
E-can - fully replenishes life energy. Player can only hold 4 cans.
Small P-chips - collect these to trade for items and powerups in Dr. Light's Lab. Each is worth 2 points.
Large P-chips - collect these to trade for items and powerups in Dr. Light's Lab. Each is worth 8 points.
Eddie - a walking can robot that can be found in some stages. He gives away a random item.
Gems - collect all 4 gems to create the Power Generator.

----------------------
Dr. Light's Lab items:
----------------------
Energy Balancer - restores weapon with the least energy when picking up weapon energy.
W-can - fully restores weapon energy of one weapon.
S-can - fully restores all life and weapons energy.
Magic Hand - the Roll Arm can grab items from afar.
Roll Claw - the Roll Arm can grab and attack the enemy continuously.
Weapon Charger - fully restores all your weapons energy. Can be done in the Lab.
Power Generator - created by collecting the 4 Gems. Reduces weapon energy consumption by half.

--------
Weapons:
--------
RO - Roll Buster 	- Default weapon. Hold down the B-button to shoot the Roll Arm.
TC - Tango Coil		- A spring adaptor for Tango. Used for jumping on high platforms. Obtained after defeating Venus.
TJ - Tango Jet		- A jet board adaptor for Tango. Flies in a straight line. Obtained after defeating Saturn.
ME - Grab Buster	- Weapon got from Mercury. Extract small life energy from enemies.
NE - Salt Water		- Weapon got from Neptune. Throw a ball of water that scatters on surfaces.
MA - Photon Missile	- Weapon got from Mars. Fire missiles with delayed launch.
VE - Bubble Bomb	- Weapon got from Venus. Throw bubble bombs that float and crawl on the ceilings.
PL - Break dash		- Weapon got from Pluto. Perform a physical dash into enemies that can also break down walls. Hold B-button to charge it.
UR - Deep Digger	- Weapon got from Uranus. Lift up blocks that can be used as projectiles.
JU - Electric Shock	- Weapon got from Jupiter. A short range weapon. Hold down B-button for continuous zapping.
SA - Black Hole		- Weapon got from Saturn. Cast a black hole that drags enemies into it. Also scatters 4 orbs around it.
TE - Spark Chaser	- Weapon got from Terra. A laser beam that chases the enemy.
TA - Tango		- Summon Tango the robot cat to help attack enemies with his spinning attack.

----
Tip:
----
Get over 4 Game Overs in one stage and you will start in Dr. Light's Lab. The good doctor will enhance your Roll Buster making it shoot and charge faster.

-------------
Known issues:
-------------
*Roll's Deep Digger sprite has her hair cut off. But the other sprites are okay.
Please contact the author if you have a solution. Any help is appreciated.

---------
ZIP file:
---------
ROLL-CHAN WORLD 5_GB folder
1. This readme
2. RW5-GB-CLASSIC.ips
3. RW5-GB-MM8.ips

-----------------
How to use patch:
-----------------
Use Lunar IPS to apply patches. Do not apply one patch over the other. Refer to the ROM Information on which ROM the patch is to be applied over.

----------------
ROM Information:
----------------
File Name:	Megaman V (U) [S][!].gb	
File Size:	524,288	
CRC32:		72E6D21D
MD5:		CEB17D831B410D91AA41BF2819CBED82
SHA1:		9A7DA0E4D3F49E4A0B94E85CD64E28A687D81260

--------
Credits:
--------
Zynk Oxhyde - Hacking and Sprites and illustrations

----------
Utilities:
----------
YY-CHR by YY
WindHex hex editor by Bongo`
bgb emulator - http://bgb.bircd.org/

---------------
Special Thanks:
---------------
Romhacking.net 	- for hosting the patch
Sprite's Inc. 	- for the ripped sprites of Roll from various Rockman/Mega Man games (http://www.sprites-inc.co.uk/)
Joseph Collins	- bug report on texts

--------
Contact:
--------
Email: zynkoxhyde@yahoo.com

----------------------------
Disclaimer and Terms of Use:
----------------------------
*Zynk Oxhyde is not related or affiliated with Nintendo and the publisher of the original game.
*Do not sell this patch and the contents with it.
*Do not sell the pre-patched ROM into reproduction cartridges.
*You may distribute or host this patch provided that all files that come with it are intact.