Thank you for downloading the Hardcore Tetris

IMPORTANT INSTRUCTIONS

First, Download BizHawk and the prerequesites here:
https://github.com/TASVideos/BizHawk-Prereqs/releases
https://github.com/TASVideos/BizHawk/releases/

Second, Install the prerequesites so that BizHawk can run.

Third, Extract BizHawk to wherever you want.

After you do that, copy the folders included in the ZIP file to the BizHawk folder.

Now, find the Game Boy Tetris ROMs;
Tetris (JUE) (v1.0) [!].gb or Tetris (World).gb
Tetris (JUE) (v1.1) [!].gb or Tetris (World) (Rev A).gb

The ROMs are not included in this package. They can be found on ROM sites.

After downloading the ROMs, make multiple copies.

Hardcore Tetris 1.0 and Classic Challenge must be patched to Tetris v1.0
Hardcore Tetris 1.1 and higher must be patched to Tetris v1.1

Make 2 copies of 1.0 and 4 copies of 1.1

Only use one patch per copy, and rename them accordingly.

Patched
Hardcore Tetris 1.0
Hardcore Tetris 1.0 Classic Challenge
Hardcore Tetris 1.1
Hardcore Tetris 1.2
Hardcore Tetris 1.3
Hardcore Tetris 1.4

Use Lunar IPS to patch the copied ROMs and place them in the Gameboy folder of BizHawk.


FREQUENTLY ASKED QUESTIONS

Q: Why aren't these patches working?
A: Because you patched the wrong version of the game.

Q: I have the (W) version but not the (JUE) version. What should I do?
A: The (W) and (JUE) versions are exactly the same.

Q: What does (Rev A) stand for?
A: A program revision is a later release of the game which includes bugfixes.

Q: Why are there versions 1.2 and later of the hack but not the game?
A: These patches are to be used with version 1.1 of the game.

Q: Level 9❤ is impossible! What should I do?
A: Additional patches (1.2 and later) have slower speeds.

Q: What is Classic Challenge and why is it for 1.0 only?
A: Classic Challenge has the same speed as 1.4. Choose your games and patches carefully.

Q: The XML files aren't working. What should I do?
A: Make sure you place the patched ROMs in the Gameboy folder of BizHawk.

Q: Why aren't the cheats working?
A: There are 2 cheat files. One is for 1.0 and the other is for 1.1.