[PAC-MAN GB - REDUX]

Original Game by: Namco
Hack by: JY
Additional Credits: ringostarr39 (Pac-Man logo, font), namcokid47 (Pac-Man font)
Platform: Game Boy
Released: September 15, 2018
Updated: December 15, 2020
Version: 1.5
Tools Used: YY-CHR, Flips
Tested on: Visual Boy Advance, BGB, original Game Boy hardware

[Hack Description]
"Pac-Man GB - Redux is a graphics hack of Pac-Man's port on Game Boy, providing a complete facelift of the entire game. The hack consists of two patches under the Pac-Man GB - Redux banner both with unique visual styles, dubbed 'Anniv. Redux' and 'Classic Redux.'

Anniv. Redux:
* Anniv. Redux features a brand new aesthetic and all-original graphics, taking full advantage of the Game Boy's limited palette and the original game's limitations. Every detail has been touched-up and redrawn, giving the game a fresh look while staying true to how Pac-Man is depicted in his series' official releases.

Classic Redux:
* New to the 1.5 release is the Classic Redux patch. Based off how the original 1990 Game Boy release looked, this alternate version of the hack aims to do a more faithful job translating the original arcade game's colorful graphics to four monochrome shades."

[Changes in 1.5]
* Brand-new Pac-Man sprites, based on his appearance in Pac-Mania.
* Edited ghost, bonus fruit sprites to match.
* Updated maze tiles in Scroll Mode.
* Brand new Pac-Man portraits in multiplayer.
* Updated title screen graphics and copyright, now reads "(c)1980, 2020 NAMCO LTD."
* Minor touch-ups on everything else.
* Introduced Classic Redux: a brand new, unique patch separate from the original Pac-Man GB - Redux hack. (now referred to as Anniv. Redux as of the release of 1.5)

[Changes in 1.0.1]
* The "B" on the game's logo, which was drawn incorrectly in 1.0, has been fixed in this release.
* A misplaced pixel on the second frame of Pac-Man's vertical animation (1/2 Mode) has been positioned correctly.
* The maze in 1/2 Mode has been touched up for the most part, fixing various minor visual inconsistencies from 1.0. The remaining visual issues that can be seen in this mode are more of a result of how the tiles were arranged to appear in-game, so those errors couldn't be accounted for without inadvertently causing more visual errors in their place.