ROLL-CHAN WORLD 3
Hacked by Zynk Oxhyde
2017

--------------
Date Released:
--------------
v1.0 March 26, 2017; In commemoration of Rockman/Mega Man 29th Anniversary and beyond! Yay! XD

------------
Description:
------------
This is a player sprite hack of "Mega Man III" for the Gameboy!
This hack changes Mega Man's player sprites and other illustrations of him into his sister Roll! 

------
Story:
------
With him barely escaped his crash landing into the sea, Dr. Wily continues his conquest for revenge 
against Roll. He has it well planned, as Dr. Wily managed to install a castle in a desolate area and 
another hidden beneath the ocean! Each castle has four Robot Masters guarding it, aside from the new
"Roll Killer" named Punk.

The battle continues and Roll with her robot cat Tango joining her once more. Also Eddie, the mobile 
cannister, is dispatched to support her. And the mysterious Proto Man seems to aid her from
the shadows.

FIGHT, ROLL! FOR EVERLASTING PEACE ONCE MORE!!

--------
Changes:
--------
(v1.0 - 03/26/2017)
*New Roll-chan player sprites
*New Get Weapon illustration
*Titlescreen modified
*New fonts
*Fixed Dr. Wily's palettes
*Rush Coil to Tango Coil
*Rush Jet to Tango Jet
*Spark Man's face fixed, other Robot Masters has minor face fixes
*Ending sprites

---------
Controls:
---------
A - Jump
B - Shoot; Hold it down for a Charged Shot
Left/Right - Run
Up/Down - Climb ladders
A+Down - Slide
Start - Weapons Menu

------
Items:
------
Small life energy
Large life energy
Small weapon energy
Large weapon energy
1UP
E-can - fully replenishes life energy. Player can only hold 4 cans.

--------
Weapons:
--------
RO - Roll Buster 	- Default weapon. Hold down the B-button for a Charged Shot.
TC - Tango Coil		- A spring adaptor for Tango. Used for jumping on high platforms. Obtained after defeating Snake Man.
TJ - Tango Jet		- A jet board adaptor for Tango. Flies in a straight line. Obtained after defeating Dust Man.
SP - Spark Shock	- Weapon got from Spark Man. Stuns an enemy on the spot. Very useful throughout the game.
SN - Search Snake	- Weapon got from Snake Man. Shoot out snake bots that can crawl upon to walls.
GE - Gemini Laser	- Weapon got from Gemini Man. A laser beam that bounces off walls.
SH - Shadow Blade	- Weapon got from Shadow Man. A ninja shuriken that acts like a boomerang. Can be thrown upwards.
DU - Dust Crusher	- Weapon got from Dust Man. A junk projectile that scatters upon enemy contact.
SK - Skull Barrier	- Weapon got from Skull Man. Skulls spins around the player that can protect against small enemies.
DI - Dive Missile	- Weapon got from Dive Man. A homing projectile that locks on its traget.
DR - Drill Bomb		- Weapon got from Drill Man. A drill that explodes and can be detonated when pressing the B-button. Can destroy blockades.
PU - Screw Crusher	- Weapon got from Punk. A spinning ball tossed in short range.

---------
ZIP file:
---------
ROLL-CHAN WORLD 3_GB folder
1. This readme
2. RW3-GB-CLASSIC.ips
3. RW3-GB-MM8.ips

-----------------
How to use patch:
-----------------
Use Lunar IPS to apply patches. Do not apply one patch over the other. Refer to the ROM Information on which ROM the patch is to be applied over.

----------------
ROM Information:
----------------
File Name:	Megaman III (U) [!].gb
File Size:	262,144	
CRC32:		5175D761
MD5:		4C614F884A07872F12056AD1A421E1F9
SHA1:		57347305AB297DAA4332564623C4A098E6DBB1A3

--------
Credits:
--------
Zynk Oxhyde - Hacking and Sprites and illustrations

----------
Utilities:
----------
YY-CHR by YY
WindHex hex editor by Bongo`
bgb emulator - http://bgb.bircd.org/

---------------
Special Thanks:
---------------
Romhacking.net 	- for hosting the patch
Sprite's Inc. 	- for the ripped sprites of Roll from various Rockman/Mega Man games (http://www.sprites-inc.co.uk/)

--------
Contact:
--------
Email: zynkoxhyde@yahoo.com

----------------------------
Disclaimer and Terms of Use:
----------------------------
*Zynk Oxhyde is not related or affiliated with Nintendo and the publisher of the original game.
*Do not sell this patch and the contents with it.
*Do not sell the pre-patched ROM into reproduction cartridges.
*You may distribute or host this patch provided that all files that come with it are intact.