ROLL-CHAN WORLD 2
Hacked by Zynk Oxhyde
2017

--------------
Date Released:
--------------
v1.0 March 26, 2017; In commemoration of Rockman/Mega Man 29th Anniversary and beyond! Yay! XD

------------
Description:
------------
This is a player sprite hack of "Mega Man II" for the Gameboy!
This hack changes Mega Man's player sprites and other illustrations of him into his sister Roll! 

------
Story:
------
Dr. Wily's revenge was unsuccessful, but he never fails on conceiving a backup plan. 
The evil doctor have stolen a time machine and plans to go back into the past. 
However, the time machine was incomplete and he did the modifications to complete it.
After that, he inadvertently made the time machine move only into the future.
With that in hand, he went to the future and discovered the world is at peace without 
a trace of him conquering it. He met his future self who was reformed and retired from
world domination. He also discovered that the Super Fighting Robot Girl was remodeled 
back into Dr. Light's housekeeping robot, Roll. Dr. Wily revised his strategem, he was
able to convince his future self to help him kidnap future Roll and reprogram her to fight 
against the Roll from his time. With the future's technology they were able to recreate
future Roll into a brainwashed Battle Robot Girl, renamed Quart. With Quart in tow back 
into his own time, Dr. Wily managed to construct an underground castle and another space station!

Roll is prepared to counterattack the evil scientist's revenge with the help of her robot cat, Tango!
And she will have a showdown with her future self, Quart, who wields a pogo stick jack hammer called
the Sakugarne.

FIGHT, ROLL! FOR EVERLASTING PEACE ONCE MORE!!

--------
Changes:
--------
(v1.1 - 06/15/2017)
*Fixed missed CLash to CRash

(v1.0 - 03/26/2017) - initial release
*New Roll-chan player sprites
*New Get Weapon illustration
*Titlescreen modified
*New fonts
*Rush Coil to Tango Coil
*Rush Marine to Tango Diver
*Rush Jet to Broom Jet
*Sprites of Dr. Wily's Machines are greatly improved!
*Quint to Quart (Note: Her name is from "Quartet" as Quint from "Quintet", a musical term)
*Fixed Dr. Wily's palettes
*Ending sprites
*Batton, Kaettekita Monking, Mag Fly, Peterchy, Scworm, Hammer Joe, Matasaburo sprites fixed
*Crash Man sprites improved; CLash to CRash

---------
Controls:
---------
A - Jump
B - Shoot
Left/Right - Run
Up/Down - Climb ladders
A+Down - Slide
Start - Weapons Menu

------
Items:
------
Small life energy
Large life energy
Small weapon energy
Large weapon energy
1UP
E-can - fully replenishes life energy. Player can only hold 4 cans.

--------
Weapons:
--------
RO - Roll Buster 	- Default weapon.
TC - Tango Coil		- A spring adaptor for Tango. Used for jumping on high platforms. Obtained after defeating Air Man.
TD - Tango Diver	- A submarine adaptor for Tango. Can shoot underwater. Obtained after defeating Metal Man.
BR - Broom Jet		- A support unit. Used as a flying transportation and can fly in any direction. Cannot be used underwater.
AI - Air Shooter	- Weapon got from Air Man. Three tornadoes flies upwards.
CR - Crash Bomb 	- Weapon got from Crash Man. Latches on walls then explodes within seconds.
ME - Metal Blade 	- Weapon got from Metal Man. Can be shot on different directions.
WO - Leaf Shield 	- Weapon got from Wood Man. Leaves revolve around the player. Can be thrown by pushing the D-pad in horizontal or vertical direction.
NE - Needle Cannon	- Weapon got from Needle Man. Holding the B-button shoots needles continuously with varying heights.
MA - Magnet Missile	- Weapon got from Magnet Man. Like homing missiles, flies vertically towards enemies.
HA - Hard Knuckle	- Weapon got from Hard Man. A large knuckle that can break down blockades.
TO - Top Spin		- Weapon got from Top Man. A close quarter attack. The player attacks with spinning body while jumping only.
SA - Sakugarne		- Weapon got from Quart. A pogo stick jackhammer weapon that the player can ride on. Press B-button to summon it. Hold down A-button to jump higher.


-------------
Known issues:
-------------
*The game is known to have many issues graphically, i.e. the player sprites.
Please contact the author. Any help is appreciated.

---------
ZIP file:
---------
ROLL-CHAN WORLD 2_GB folder
1. This readme
2. RW2-GB-CLASSIC.ips
3. RW2-GB-MM8.ips

-----------------
How to use patch:
-----------------
Use Lunar IPS to apply patches. Do not apply one patch over the other. Refer to the ROM Information on which ROM the patch is to be applied over.

----------------
ROM Information:
----------------
File Name:	Megaman II (U) [!].gb	
File Size:	262,144	
CRC32:		E496F686
MD5:		7FE07271D04ED9E0BC0663DDE55A2AE4	
SHA1:		334F1A93346D55E1BE2967F0AF952E37AA52FCA7

--------
Credits:
--------
Zynk Oxhyde - Hacking and Sprites and illustrations

----------
Utilities:
----------
YY-CHR by YY
WindHex hex editor by Bongo`
bgb emulator - http://bgb.bircd.org/

---------------
Special Thanks:
---------------
Romhacking.net 	- for hosting the patch
Sprite's Inc. 	- for the ripped sprites of Roll from various Rockman/Mega Man games (http://www.sprites-inc.co.uk/)
Zeikar 		- for reporting the missed CLash to CRash edit

--------
Contact:
--------
Email: zynkoxhyde@yahoo.com

----------------------------
Disclaimer and Terms of Use:
----------------------------
*Zynk Oxhyde is not related or affiliated with Nintendo and the publisher of the original game.
*Do not sell this patch and the contents with it.
*Do not sell the pre-patched ROM into reproduction cartridges.
*You may distribute or host this patch provided that all files that come with it are intact.