████     ███   ██████████████████████
█░░░█    █░░█ █░░█░░░░░█░░░░░█░░░█░░░█
██░█░███  █░░█░░███░█░███░█░░██░█░░█░░█
 █░█░█░░█ █░░░░░██░░░░░██░░░███░█░░█░░█
█░░░▒█░▒██░░░█░░░░░░█░░░░░█░░░░░░█░░░▒█
█▒▒▒██▒█░█▒▒▒█▒▒▒▒▒▒█▒▒▒▒▒█▒▒▒▒▒▒█▒▒▒█
█████████████████████████████████████

     ███ ███ ██ █ ███ █  █ ███ ██
 ██  ██  ██  █ ██ ██  █ ██ ██  █ █ ██
     █ █ ███ █  █ ███ ██ █ ███ ███

█ █ █ █ █ █ █ █ █ █ █ █ █ █ █
 █ █ █ █ █ █ █ █ █ █ █ █ █ █ 


*Original Game by: Nintendo
        *Hack by: JY
    *Platform: Game Boy
       *Released: TBD
       *Version: 1.0
    *Tools Used: YY-CHR,
    Flips (Floating IPS)
*Tested on: VisualBoyAdvance,
        BizHawk, BGB


 █ █ █ █ █ █ █ █ █ █ █ █ █ █ 
█ █ █ █ █ █ █ █ █ █ █ █ █ █ █


[Hack Description]
"Dr. Mario - Renewed" is a hack of Dr. Mario, not on the NES but rather on the Game Boy.

While this hack still retains the familiar "match four" gameplay in all its 1990 glory, the same can't be said for the visuals. Just about every graphic found within the game has since been updated and redrawn, all in an effort to present the beloved puzzle game with a more refined aesthetic for Game Boy players.


 █ █ █ █ █ █ █ █ █ █ █ █ █ █ 
█ █ █ █ █ █ █ █ █ █ █ █ █ █ █


[Patching Instructions]
For those in posession of the "Dr. Mario (World).gb" ROM, it's recommended to create a backup before starting, just to have a good copy left over should anything go wrong with the patching process. For those without the necessary ROM, this document is legally prohibited from providing sources or otherwise pointing to where the ROM can be acquired. For that reason, you will have to search out the ROM on your own if you do not already have one.

1. Open "flips.exe." If you don't already have Flips downloaded, you can download the utility from ROMhacking.net by following this link: https://www.romhacking.net/utilities/1040/

2. When given your options upon booting the program, choose "Apply Patch"; this will create a new copy of the Dr. Mario ROM based on the patch data.

3. After being given the "Select Patches to Use" prompt, select the .bps file "Dr. Mario - Renewed". You'll then be prompted to "Select a File to Patch". After reaching this step of the process, be sure to select an unaltered version of the "Dr. Mario (World).gb" ROM.

4. When given the "Select Output File" prompt, enter the desired name of your ROM in the "File name" field and click "Save." Otherwise, the name of the output ROM file will default to that of the patch, or "Dr. Mario - Renewed" in this case.

If all went well, a pop-up window will appear confirming that the patch was applied successfully and from here, you will now be able to play the hack.